[
  {
    "question": "lase",
    "answer": "hair"
  },
  {
    "question": "prsti na roki",
    "answer": "fingers"
  },
  {
    "question": "nos",
    "answer": "nose"
  },
  {
    "question": "prsti na nogi",
    "answer": "toes"
  },
  {
    "question": "vrat",
    "answer": "neck"
  },
  {
    "question": "lica",
    "answer": "cheeks"
  },
  {
    "question": "obraz",
    "answer": "face"
  },
  {
    "question": "ušesa",
    "answer": "ears"
  },
  {
    "question": "obrvi",
    "answer": "eyebrows"
  },
  {
    "question": "brada (del obraza)",
    "answer": "chin"
  },
  {
    "question": "oči",
    "answer": "eyes"
  },
  {
    "question": "zobje",
    "answer": "teeth"
  },
  {
    "question": "glava",
    "answer": "head"
  },
  {
    "question": "usta",
    "answer": "mouth"
  },
  {
    "question": "roka",
    "answer": "arm"
  },
  {
    "question": "dlan",
    "answer": "hand"
  },
  {
    "question": "noga",
    "answer": "leg"
  },
  {
    "question": "stopalo",
    "answer": "foot"
  },
  {
    "question": "telo",
    "answer": "body"
  },
  {
    "question": "rama",
    "answer": "shoulder"
  },
  {
    "question": "komolec",
    "answer": "elbow"
  },
  {
    "question": "trebuh",
    "answer": "stomach"
  },
  {
    "question": "modre oči",
    "answer": "blue eyes"
  },
  {
    "question": "majhen nos",
    "answer": "small nose"
  },
  {
    "question": "okrogla usta",
    "answer": "round mouth"
  },
  {
    "question": "lep obraz",
    "answer": "pretty face"
  },
  {
    "question": "svetli lasje",
    "answer": "blond hair"
  },
  {
    "question": "dolg vrat",
    "answer": "long neck"
  },
  {
    "question": "beli zobje",
    "answer": "white teeth"
  },
  {
    "question": "tanke obrvi",
    "answer": "thin eyebrows"
  },
  {
    "question": "kratki kodrasti svetli lasje",
    "answer": "short curly fair hair"
  },
  {
    "question": "dolgi ravni lasje",
    "answer": "long straight hair"
  },
  {
    "question": "kratki kodrasti črni lasje",
    "answer": "short curly black hair"
  },
  {
    "question": "dolgi ravni srednje dolgi lasje",
    "answer": "long straight medium hair"
  },
  {
    "question": "kratki valoviti blond lasje",
    "answer": "short wavy blond hair"
  },
  {
    "question": "dolgi ravni blond lasje",
    "answer": "long straight blonde hair"
  },
  {
    "question": "kratki rjavi lasje",
    "answer": "short brown hair"
  },
  {
    "question": "dolgi valoviti rjavi lasje",
    "answer": "long wavy brown hair"
  },
  {
    "question": "ima frizuro na ježka",
    "answer": "he has a crew cut"
  },
  {
    "question": "ima kitke",
    "answer": "she has pigtails"
  },
  {
    "question": "je plešast",
    "answer": "he is bald"
  },
  {
    "question": "ima kito",
    "answer": "she has a plait"
  },
  {
    "question": "ima čop",
    "answer": "she has a ponytail"
  },
  {
    "question": "ima frufru",
    "answer": "she has a fringe"
  },
  {
    "question": "žalosten",
    "answer": "sad"
  },
  {
    "question": "jezen",
    "answer": "angry"
  },
  {
    "question": "ponosen",
    "answer": "proud"
  },
  {
    "question": "prestrašen",
    "answer": "scared"
  },
  {
    "question": "resen",
    "answer": "serious"
  },
  {
    "question": "vesel",
    "answer": "happy"
  },

  {
    "question": "Gor in dol.",
    "answer": "Up and down."
  },
  {
    "question": "Desno in levo.",
    "answer": "Right and left."
  },
  {
    "question": "Zapri oči.",
    "answer": "Close your eyes."
  },
  {
    "question": "Pokimaj z glavo.",
    "answer": "Nod your head."
  },
  {
    "question": "Migaj z ušesi.",
    "answer": "Wiggle your ears."
  },
  {
    "question": "Sedi na posteljo.",
    "answer": "Sit on your bed."
  },
  {
    "question": "To je Joejev nos.",
    "answer": "This is Joe's nose."
  },
  {
    "question": "To so Joejeva usta.",
    "answer": "This is Joe's mouth."
  },
  {
    "question": "To je Joejevo oko.",
    "answer": "This is Joe's eye."
  },
  {
    "question": "To je Joejevo uho.",
    "answer": "This is Joe's ear."
  },
  {
    "question": "To so Joejevi lasje.",
    "answer": "This is Joe's hair."
  },
  {
    "question": "Vesela je, ko dobi darilo.",
    "answer": "She’s happy when she gets a present."
  },
  {
    "question": "Žalostna je, ko se ne more igrati.",
    "answer": "She’s sad when she can’t play with her friends."
  },
  {
    "question": "Resna je, ko dela domačo nalogo.",
    "answer": "She’s serious when she does her homework."
  },
  {
    "question": "Ponosna je, ko dobi dobro oceno.",
    "answer": "She’s proud when she gets a good mark."
  },
  {
    "question": "Jezna je, ko se prijatelji norčujejo.",
    "answer": "She’s angry when friends play tricks on her."
  },
  {
    "question": "Prestrašena je, ko vidi kačo.",
    "answer": "She’s scared when she sees a snake."
  },
  {
    "question": "Ko sem žalosten, jokam.",
    "answer": "When I’m sad, I cry."
  },
  {
    "question": "Ko sem radoveden, sprašujem.",
    "answer": "When I’m curious, I ask."
  },
  {
    "question": "Ko mi je dolgčas, spim.",
    "answer": "When I’m bored, I sleep."
  },
  {
    "question": "Ko sem vesel, se smejim.",
    "answer": "When I’m happy, I smile."
  },
  {
    "question": "Ko sem sramežljiv, se skrijem.",
    "answer": "When I’m shy, I hide."
  },
  {
    "question": "Ko sem prestrašen, kričim.",
    "answer": "When I’m scared, I scream."
  },
  {
    "question": "Ko sem ljubeč, poljubim.",
    "answer": "When I’m loving, I kiss."
  },
  {
    "question": "Ko sem zmeden, skomignem.",
    "answer": "When I’m puzzled, I shrug."
  },
  {
    "question": "Kaj lahko tvoje oči delajo?",
    "answer": "They can see."
  },
  {
    "question": "Kaj lahko tvoji zobje delajo?",
    "answer": "They can chew."
  },
  {
    "question": "Kaj lahko tvoja ušesa delajo?",
    "answer": "They can hear."
  },
  {
    "question": "Kaj lahko tvoje roke delajo?",
    "answer": "They can hug."
  },
  {
    "question": "Kaj lahko tvoji prsti delajo?",
    "answer": "They can touch."
  },
  {
    "question": "Kaj lahko tvoj hrbet dela?",
    "answer": "It can bend."
  },
  {
    "question": "Kaj lahko tvoje noge delajo?",
    "answer": "They can run."
  },
  {
    "question": "Kaj lahko tvoja usta delajo?",
    "answer": "It can kiss."
  },
  {
    "question": "Kaj lahko tvoj nos dela?",
    "answer": "It can smell."
  },
  {
    "question": "Kaj lahko tvoje roke naredijo?",
    "answer": "They can clap."
  },
  {
    "question": "Kaj lahko tvoja glava naredi?",
    "answer": "It can nod."
  },
  {
    "question": "Ali lahko igraš košarko z eno roko?",
    "answer": "Can you play basketball with one hand?"
  },
  {
    "question": "Ali lahko daš noge za vrat?",
    "answer": "Can you put your legs behind your neck?"
  },
  {
    "question": "Ali lahko žvižgaš s prsti?",
    "answer": "Can you whistle with your fingers?"
  },
  {
    "question": "Ali lahko migljaš z ušesi?",
    "answer": "Can you wiggle your ears?"
  },
  {
    "question": "Ali se lahko dotakneš kolen z nosom?",
    "answer": "Can you touch your knees with your nose?"
  },
  {
    "question": "Ali lahko hodiš po rokah?",
    "answer": "Can you walk on your hands?"
  },
  {
    "question": "Ali lahko stojiš na glavi?",
    "answer": "Can you stand on your head?"
  },

  {
    "question": "Vidim tri glave.",
    "answer": "I can see three heads."
  },
  {
    "question": "Vidim štiri roke.",
    "answer": "I can see four arms."
  },
  {
    "question": "Vidim sedem oči.",
    "answer": "I can see seven eyes."
  },
  {
    "question": "Vidim štiri dlani.",
    "answer": "I can see four hands."
  },
  {
    "question": "Vidim tri usta.",
    "answer": "I can see three mouths."
  },
  {
    "question": "Vidim dvanajst prstov.",
    "answer": "I can see twelve fingers."
  },
  {
    "question": "Vidim šest ušes.",
    "answer": "I can see six ears."
  },
  {
    "question": "Vidim tri noge.",
    "answer": "I can see three legs."
  },
  {
    "question": "Vidim sedem zob.",
    "answer": "I can see seven teeth."
  },
  {
    "question": "Vidim tri stopala.",
    "answer": "I can see three feet."
  },
  {
    "question": "Vidim tri nosove.",
    "answer": "I can see three noses."
  },
  {
    "question": "Vidim devet prstov na nogi.",
    "answer": "I can see nine toes."
  },
  {
    "question": "Dve majhni očki, da gledata okrog.",
    "answer": "Two little eyes to look around."
  },
  {
    "question": "Dve majhni ušesi, da slišita vsak zvok.",
    "answer": "Two little ears to hear each sound."
  },
  {
    "question": "En majhen nos, da voha, kar je sladko.",
    "answer": "One little nose to smell what's sweet."
  },
  {
    "question": "Ena majhna usta, ki rada jedo.",
    "answer": "One little mouth that likes to eat."
  },
  {
    "question": "Njene oči lahko mežikajo.",
    "answer": "Her eyes can wink."
  },
  {
    "question": "Njena stopala lahko tečejo.",
    "answer": "Her feet can run."
  },
  {
    "question": "Njena roka lahko maha.",
    "answer": "Her hand can wave."
  },
  {
    "question": "Njena ušesa lahko migajo.",
    "answer": "Her ears can wiggle."
  },
  {
    "question": "Njena usta lahko rečejo živjo.",
    "answer": "Her mouth can say hello."
  },
  {
    "question": "Njeni prsti lahko pokažejo.",
    "answer": "Her fingers can point."
  },
  {
    "question": "Njena glava lahko kima.",
    "answer": "Her head can nod."
  },
  {
    "question": "Ima usta, a ne more govoriti.",
    "answer": "It has a mouth but cannot talk."
  },
  {
    "question": "Ima štiri noge, a ne more hoditi.",
    "answer": "It has four legs but cannot walk."
  },
  {
    "question": "Ima močna stopala, a ne more teči.",
    "answer": "It has strong feet but cannot run."
  },
  {
    "question": "Ima štiri noge in glavo. Kaj je to?",
    "answer": "It has four feet and a head. What is it?"
  },
  {
    "question": "Je to postelja?",
    "answer": "Is it a bed?"
  },
  {
    "question": "Deček vsak dan kolesari.",
    "answer": "The boy cycles every day."
  },
  {
    "question": "Njegov najljubši šport je kolesarjenje.",
    "answer": "His favourite sport is cycling."
  },
  {
    "question": "Fantje vsak dan tečejo.",
    "answer": "The boys run every day."
  },
  {
    "question": "Njihov najljubši šport je tek.",
    "answer": "Their favourite sport is running."
  },
  {
    "question": "Deklica pleza ob sobotah.",
    "answer": "The girl climbs on Saturdays."
  },
  {
    "question": "Njen najljubši šport je plezanje.",
    "answer": "Her favourite sport is climbing."
  },
  {
    "question": "Deklice igrajo odbojko vsak vikend.",
    "answer": "The girls play volleyball every weekend."
  },
  {
    "question": "Njihov najljubši šport je odbojka.",
    "answer": "Their favourite sport is volleyball."
  },
  {
    "question": "Fantje trenirajo karate ob sobotah.",
    "answer": "The boys do karate on Saturdays."
  },
  {
    "question": "Njihov najljubši šport je karate.",
    "answer": "Their favourite sport is karate."
  },
  {
    "question": "Deklice rolajo poleti.",
    "answer": "The girls roller-skate in summer."
  },
  {
    "question": "Njihov najljubši šport je rolanje.",
    "answer": "Their favourite sport is roller-skating."
  },
  {
    "question": "Star mož čuti, da se mu bliža smrt.",
    "answer": "An old man feels the death is close."
  },
  {
    "question": "Hoče dati sinovom pomemben nasvet.",
    "answer": "He wants to give his sons some important advice."
  },
  {
    "question": "Pokliče sinove k postelji.",
    "answer": "He calls his sons to his bed."
  },
  {
    "question": "Ukaže naj prinesejo šop palic.",
    "answer": "He orders his servants to bring in a bundle of sticks."
  },
  {
    "question": "Reče najstarejšemu sinu naj zlomi.",
    "answer": "He says to his eldest son: 'Break it.'"
  },
  {
    "question": "Sin ne more zlomiti šopa.",
    "answer": "The son tries and tries but can't break the bundle."
  },
  {
    "question": "Drugi sinovi tudi ne uspejo.",
    "answer": "The other sons also try but none of them is successful."
  },
  {
    "question": "Oče reče naj razvežejo šop.",
    "answer": "'Untie the bundle,' says the father."
  },
  {
    "question": "Vsak naj vzame palico.",
    "answer": "'And each of you take a stick.'"
  },
  {
    "question": "Vsaka palica se zlahka zlomi.",
    "answer": "Then each stick is easily broken."
  },
  {
    "question": "Zdaj razumete moj nasvet.",
    "answer": "'You understand my advice now,' said their father."
  },
  {
    "question": "V slogi je moč.",
    "answer": "There is strength in unity."
  },
  {
    "question": "Rdeča kapica.",
    "answer": "Little Red Riding Hood."
  },
  {
    "question": "košara",
    "answer": "basket"
  },
  {
    "question": "babica",
    "answer": "grandma"
  },
  {
    "question": "mama",
    "answer": "mother"
  },
  {
    "question": "hiša",
    "answer": "house"
  },
  {
    "question": "gozd",
    "answer": "forest"
  },
  {
    "question": "volk",
    "answer": "wolf"
  },
  {
    "question": "lovec",
    "answer": "hunter"
  }
]
